ILGWU. Jay Mazur papers, 5780/203
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series V. AFL-CIO
  - AFL-CIO Executive Council, May, 1992 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    Statements of the Executive Council on: Article XX Protection for Independent Unions, the Balanced Budget Amendment, the President's "Beck" Orders (Executive Order re NLRB, union organizing), AFL-CIO retiree organizations, U.S. corporations and international worker rights, unemployment compensation, United Way of America; draft amendments to AFL-CIO constitution; report to the Executive Council by the Committee on Older and Retired Union Members; organizing report; press release re Roper poll re striker replacement ban, "Public Favors Workplace Fairness Bill by 72 Percent"; letter sent to members of Congress, supporting reauthorization of the language assistance provisions of the Voting Right Act
  - AFL-CIO Executive Council, reports, 1992-1994 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    See also Committee on Political Education (COPE) 1994 Outlook Report 1993-94, listing congressional and gubernatorial races, February 16-19, 1993; Executive Council Meeting COPE Report 1994; AFL-CIO Housing Investment Trust Report to Executive Council 2/92
  - AFL-CIO Executive Council, July, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    See also Industrial Union Department (IUD) Legislative Committee Reports: "Overview of the Impact of the Collapse of the Executive Life Insurance Company," prepared by the Employee Benefits Department; survey on retiree groups; Labor Day statement by the U.S. Catholic Conference; report of standing committee on Safety and Occupational Health; report of ad hoc committee on the Harvard Trade Union Program; statements of the Executive Council on: reinforcing China's dictatorship, unemployment insurance, South Africa, meeting the needs of children, Yugoslavia; list of publishing scam operations targeting union locals; presidential process voluntary guidelines re endorsements; report by Mazur on Industrial Union Department's (IUD) Legislative Program, July 17; resolution on Workplace Fairness Bill, September 13
  - AFL-CIO Executive Council, February, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    See also Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) – Support Group 1990-1991 Report of the Organizing Institute; report/description of the Organization and Field Service Department; draft report on advisory committee meetings for Asian American support group; report of Committee on Asian/American Labor Support Group; Department of International Affairs Subcommittee on Perestroika Chairman's Report to the Executive Council of the AFL-CIO; resolutions of Industrial Union Department (IUD) for consideration by AFL-CIO Executive Council: "Protect U.S. Mainland Jobs," and "America's Choice: High Skills or Low Wages"; correspondence with Hotel Employees & Restaurant Employees (HERE) Union local 11; written testimony of the American Chiropractic Association in support of the AFL-CIO's campaign for health care reform; statements of Executive Council on: abuse of "Section 936" of the tax code, anti-recession programs, black Revolutionary War patriots memorial, the continued threat of corporate takeovers, foreign control of U.S. aviation industry, democratic transition in South Africa, George Many commemorative stamp, employee privacy, minimum wage, opposition to limiting terms of office, Operation Stateside (Red Cross program to support families of military personnel serving in Persian Gulf war), prison labor programs; printed booklet of statements adopted by the AFL-CIO Executive Council, February 1990
  - Executive Council minutes from November 9, 13 and 14, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    Indexed by subject
  - AFL-CIO Executive Council, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    See also AFL-CIO 1988- 1990 Draft statements by Executive Council re Social Security, Cuba, U.N. World Summit for Children, strikers' rights legislation, South Africa and free trade unionism, budget negotiations, campaign finance and the Senate, the Hatch Act, reproductive issues (with accompanying committee report), and report by Committee on Older and Retired Union Members, August 1990; Roper Report survey, May 17, 1990; information packet for Executive Council meeting of July 31-August 2, 1990, mostly re reproductive issues; personal and confidential letter from Mazur to Kirkland re fast-track trade negotiation authority under GATT, December 3, 1990; letter from Mazur to Kirkland re bringing attention to plight of workers in China, December 19, 1990; letter from Mazur re commemoration of first anniversary of Tiananmen Square massacre, May 29, 1990; letter from Mazur to Kirkland re creation of Asian American support group within AFL-CIO, April 17, 1990; letter from Mazur to Kirkland re Republican plan to gerrymander black and Hispanic voters out of traditionally Democratic congressional districts after census, October 9, 1990; draft report from the AFL-CIO Industrial Union Department (IUD) re lobbying and grass-roots campaign for legislation to amend the National Labor Relations Act (NLRB) re striker replacement, July 24, 1990
  - AFL-CIO Executive Council, 1989 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    Presentation by Roper Organization, "Labor Makes a Comeback and Other Key Opinion Trends"; statement by the Executive Council on affirmative action, affordable housing for families and homeless, Burma, Central America, child labor, Chile, Eastern Airlines, industrial homework, Hungary's unions, international trade and investment, Korea, Malaysia, Maquiladora program in Mexico, minimum wage, negotiations in Poland, campaign finance reform, Histadrut and Israel, implementing the national affiliation fee, pension plan terminations, protecting the environment at Department of Energy nuclear facilities, the savings and loan failure, South Africa, tariffs, working families; reports by the Committee on Older and Retired Union Members, Committee on Occupational Safety and Health, Defense Committee re base closure, housing investment trust and building investment trust, cases filed under Article XX and XXI, organizing, Human Resources Development Institute, National Leadership Commission on Health Care; Open Response to Victor Reuther by executive officers of UAW accused of selling out to management, February 28, 1989
  - AFL-CIO Executive Council-Israel, 1988-1989 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    Statement by Dr. Rudolph Oswald, director Department of Economic research, AFL-CIO, on Workers' Rights Practices of GSP Beneficiary Countries before the GSP Subcommittee of the Trade Policy Staff Committee, objecting to investigation of labor-rights abuses by Israel, November 17 & 18, 1988; letter from AFL-CIO director of Department of International Affairs responding to letter from the president of the Arab-American Anti-Discrimination Committee concerning alleged workers' rights abuses by Israel, August 11, 1988; executive summary of testimony of the Jewish Labor Committee and the NJCRAC before the U.S. Trade Representative, February 29, 1989
  - AFL-CIO Executive Council, 1986-1989 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    See also AFL-CIO 1988-1990 Statement by the Executive Council on the national economy, February 18, 1986; draft statement on overriding the veto of the Textile and Apparel Trade Enforcement Act, August 1986; letters from Mazur re health and safety, March 14, 1989; child care, February 9, 1989; Executive Council meeting agenda; draft statements by Executive Council re Eastern Airlines strike, march for Housing Now!, 25th anniversary of Civil Rights Act, minimum wage, Solidarnosc, May 1989; list of members and union affiliations of the Executive Council, 1989; "A Warning to the Congress and the President: America Needs Increased Public Investment, Now," signed by 306 American economists, headed by Jeff Faux, Economic Policy Institute
  - AFL-CIO Executive Council reimbursement letter and forms, 1985-1990 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    Routine reimbursement forms, mostly for Executive Council meeting-related expenses, and letter of explanation by Mazur re method of calculation
  - AFL-CIO- African-American Labor Center, 1989-1992 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    Division of AFL-CIO concerned with international trade union development in Africa. Report of 1988 activities to Board of Directors meeting, held November 21, 1989; AFL-CIO Statement on Sudan, July 26, 1989; memo to Mazur proposing allocation of supplemental administrative support by ILGWU to provide salary differential, October 26, 1989; letter to Mazur from executive director re 25th anniversary conference, September 14, 1989; Resolution on Lesotho by Executive Committee of the International Textile, Garment and Leather Workers Federation, October 27-19, 1991; letter from executive director asking for help in organizing a demonstration at the Embassy of Malawi in Washington, D.C., protesting the arrest of trade unionist Chakufwa Chihana, April 30, 1992; letter to Mazur from regional representative re ILGWU organizing efforts at Domsey Trading Corp. (Brooklyn, NY), noting decree in Kenya against the importation of used clothing, difficulty of identifying clothing from Domsey, July 26, 1990; letter to Mazur from acting executive director re South African Clothing & Textile Workers Union, with attached proposal to Agency for International Development for Zenzeleni Clothing and Employment Creation Project, January 29, 1991
  - AFL-CIO- African-American Labor Center, 1986-1988 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    Letters re leadership seminars for African trade unionists, 1987-88; letter from Mazur to the executive director of African-American Labor Center re assignment of a U.S. staff member at ITGWLF headquarters in Brussels, recommendation by ILGWU for appointment of Eric Bombart as research assistant to health & safety project approved at recent ITGLWF World Congress in Tokyo, description of duties, request for funds committed to project, December 12, 1988; routine correspondence
  - AFL-CIO- American Institute for Free Labor Development, 1989-1994 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    See also Committees – Cuba Committee; see also Committees – International Organizing and Solidarity Committee; see also under specific countries Division of AFL-CIO concerned with international trade union development in Latin America. Suggested draft of speech for Mazur, as chair of the AFL-CIO Committee for a Free Cuba, for luncheon honoring Mario Chanes, August 5, 1993; excerpts from a report describing labor's role in the 1989 Salvadoran elections by the International Human Rights Law Group, March 21, 1989; solicitation from Mazur to AIFLD for continued funding of the health and safety department of the International Textile, Garment and Leather Workers' Federation, with attached description of the program, November 21, 1989; letter from finance director of AIFLD to secretary treasurer of FITITVC, asking for an accounting to back up attached balance sheets, September 25, 1989; newsletter, AIFLD Report, fourth quarter 1991; fourth quarter 1990, with cover letter to ILGWU assistant president Gus Tyler from John Justin and including article by Tyler, "Farmers, Governments, and Market Economies"; memo to Mazur from ILGWU director of Organization & Field Services expressing concerns over proposed AIFLD "Free Zone Organizing Training Program," December 1, 1992; Report on the ICFTU/ORIT Mission to Haiti, April 1986; letter to Mazur re developments in Nicaragua, with attached newsletter of the Puebla Institute, testimony of Freedom House senior associate before the U.S. House Committee on Foreign Affairs, May 24, 1991; draft of news article re Mazur visit to Nicaragua, press transcripts of inauguration speech of Violeta Chamorro, May 2, 1990; packet of newspaper clippings re Cuba, 1994
  - AFL-CIO- American Institute for Free Labor Development, 1985-1988 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    See also Tunnel Vision Notice to Mazur of annual meeting of Board of Trustees, October 24, 1988; negative reviews of Tunnel Vision: Labor, the World Economy, and Central America (Dan Cantor and Juliet Shor), a book critical of the anti-communist stance of the AFL-CIO Department of International Affairs and U.S. trade unions generally; draft of letter for Mazur to U.S. Secretary of State George Schultz to terminate aid to Pinochet regime in Chile, August 18, 1986; itinerary for trip to Central America, with trip report by Western States AFL-CIO Delegation to Central America, July 15, 1985; letter from Mazur to the executive director of AIFLD re assignment of a U.S. staff member at ITGWLF headquarters in Brussels, recommendation by ILGWU for appointment of Eric Bombart as research assistant to health & safety project approved at recent ITGLWF World Congress in Tokyo, description of duties, request for funds committed to project, December 12, 1988; routine correspondence
  - AFL-CIO- Asian-American Free Labor Institute, 1989-1991 (Box 31, Folder 26)
    see also China Division of AFL-CIO concerned with international trade union development in Asia. Memo to members of AFL-CIO's China Committee announcing Tiananmen Square demonstration at the Capitol, with attached flyer, May 28, 1991; letter to ILGWU International Relations director Michele Briones thanking her for the presentation to TEKSIF Women's Symposium held in Istanbul, Turkey, December 4, 1990; agenda for the annual meeting of the AAFLI Board of Trustees, January 8, 1991, with minutes of the December 14, 1989, meeting and report of the executive director updating activities in Korea, Taiwan, Japan, Hong Kong, Philippines, Indonesia, Burma, Thailand, China, Malaysia, Pakistan, India, Bangladesh, Nepal, Australia, New Zealand, Lebanon, Cyprus, Turkey; memo to Mazur from Briones re AAFLI meeting with Tiananmen survivor and representative of the Workers Autonomous Federation, China, May 4, 1990; Report to the Board of Trustees, 1990, "Working with the International Labor Movement in Asia and the South Pacific"; letter from Mazur to AAFLD executive director asking for continued funding of health and safety program of the International Textile, Garment and Leather Workers' Federation, with attached description of program, November 21, 1989; AAFLI newsletter, re child exploitation, January-February 1989
  - AFL-CIO- Asian-American Free Labor Institute (AAFLI), 1986-1988 (Box 31, Folder 27)
    White paper re role of trade unions and institution-building in the Philippines, April 15, 1986; correspondence re trip by ILGWU official Joe Danahy to TWARO West Asian Sub-Regional seminar to be held in Bombay, India, October 19 – November 6, 1987; correspondence re finances, repeated budget cuts, impact on AAFLI/TWARO union-to-union program, April 25, 1986 – May 13, 1988; letter to AAFLI from ILGWU International Relations assistant director Michele Briones re organizing potential in Pakistan, Malaysia, and the Philippines, TWARO program, November 6, 1986; letter to Mazur from AAFLI executive director re joint statement with Zensen (Japanese trade union organization) re Multi-Fiber Arrangement (MFA), January 7, 1988; letter from Mazur to the executive director of AAFLI re assignment of a U.S. staff member at ITGWLF headquarters in Brussels, recommendation by ILGWU to appoint Eric Bombart as research assistant to health & safety project approved at recent ITGLWF World Congress in Tokyo, description of duties, request for funds committed to project, December 12, 1988
  - AFL-CIO- Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Convention, 1992-1993 (Box 31, Folder 28)
    Division of AFL-CIO concerned with supporting Asian American union members. Letter to Mazur from AFL-CIO president Lane Kirkland summarizing accomplishments of AFL-CIO's newest labor support group, APALA, asking for recommendation for ILGWU representative to Executive Board, April 28, 1993; call to 1993 convention; letter to Mazur from Kirkland re success of founding convention call for AFL-CIO's newest labor support group, APALA, April 22, 1992; press release re founding convention, issues discussed affecting Asian Americans, May 1, 1992; conference materials including speech by Mazur, list of delegates, May 1, 1992
  - AFL-CIO-Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance Steering Committee, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    Confidential memo to Mazur from the manager of the ILGWU Pacific Northwest District Council and chair of the APALA Steering Committee, Katie Quan, expressing concern over disputes among members of the committee, particularly involving representatives from AFSCME, October 17, 1991; memo to Mazur from Quan re vote by Steering Committee on composition of Executive Board calling for ethnic, geographic, gender, and union diversity, November 8, 1991; memo to Mazur from Quan listing members of Steering Committee, November 5, 1991; minutes of the Steering Committee meeting, October 25-26; 1991; corrected minutes of the September 1-2, 1991, meeting; confidential letter to Mazur from the president of the Sheet Metal Workers' International Association, asking why a member of his union was not acceptable for appointment to the APALA Steering Committee, October 21, 1991; confidential memo to Mazur from Quan explaining allegations of exclusion by various unions, especially larger ones like AFSCME "throwing their weight around," October 30, 1991; memo to Mazur from Mike Gildea, of AFL-CIO Organization & Field Services, outlining history of decisions by APALA re composition of Steering Committee, October 31, 1991; detailed letter of explanation from Mazur to Sheet Metal Workers president, November 4, 1991; agenda and related materials for the first meeting of the Steering Committee, held June 21, 1991; remarks by Mazur at first meeting of interim steering committee, June 21, 1991; comparison of bylaws with other support groups (A. Philip Randolph Institute, Coalition of Labor Union Women, Labor Council for Latin American Advancement); letter to Mazur from the Asian Labor Committee of the New York City Central Labor Council, appealing rejection of member for Steering Committee, June 7, 1991; draft of letter to presidents of AFL-CIO unions over Mazur's signature announcing the formation of APALA, creation of interim steering committee of representatives from the unions, with editing by Mazur, May 3, 1991; letter to Mazur from United Steelworkers representative to Steering Committee, accepting position, May 11, 1991; letter to Mazur as chair of the AFL-CIO Task Force on an Asian Labor Support Group from members of the Asian American Federation of Union Members, asking that the search process for temporary staff support be opened up to all applicants and that the hiring decision rest with the Steering Committee, April 18, 1991; memo to Mazur from Katie Quan with attached resume from applicant for staff support position, April 16, 1991; nominations for Steering Committee to Mazur by the Asian Labor Committee, New York City Central Labor Council, March 27, 1991; letter to Mazur from the executive secretary-treasurer of the California Labor Federation, AFL-CIO, giving assurance of cooperation in forming an Asian Pacific American labor committee, March 22, 1991; memo to Mazur and Susan Cowell from Katie Quan listing nominees to the Steering Committee by the San Francisco ad hoc committee, March 11, 1991; Report to the Executive Council, Committee on Asian/American Labor Support Group, chairman: Jay Mazur, with statement of purpose, recommendations, statistical demographic projections for year 2000, cover letter to Quan, February 28, 1991; budget proposal for 1991; memo to Mazur from AFL-CIO's Mike Gildea re composition of Steering Committee, February 12, 1991; letter to Mazur from the president of the New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council recommending two members for the Steering Committee, January 22, 1991; memo to Mazur from Quan recommending selection of Steering Committee at the local level, financing, January 16, 1991; minutes of second meeting of Executive Council Committee on Asian Support Group, January 10, 1991; handwritten notes by Mazur; newspaper clippings
  - AFL-CIO-Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance Support Group, 1990-1991 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    See also AFL-CIO Executive Council 2/18/91 Proposal for a Nationwide Asian Pacific American Labor Organization, by the San Francisco Ad Hoc Committee, September 1990; list of Asian American leaders of Bay Area (San Francisco, CA) unions, September 1990; Asian Support Committee confidential memorandum of meeting with Mazur, July 12, 1990; draft budget; conference brochure and related materials; expense statement for San Francisco Chinatown Garment Workers Center; letter from Mazur to AFL-CIO president Lane Kirkland updating him on the work of the Asian American Support Committee, with attached Preliminary Results, Survey of Asian American Union Membership, December 20, 1990; Los Angeles Newspaper Guild Resolution to Support a National Asian Pacific American Labor Committee, April 20, 1991, with cover letter to Mazur re anticipated resolutions from other unions, May 16, 1991; correspondence; newspaper clippings; handwritten notes by Mazur
  - AFL-CIO-Civil Rights Department, 1990-1991 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    Civil rights organizing project questionnaire, with cover letter to Mazur from Lenore Miller, chair of the AFL-CIO Civil Rights Committee, October 10, 1990; letter to Mazur re appointment to the AFL-CIO Civil Rights Committee, March 5, 1991
  - AFL-CIO-Committees (standing), 1989-1995 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    Lists of standing committees and members, with cover letters to Mazur from AFL-CIO president Lane Kirkland
  - AFL-CIO-Committees (ad-hoc), 1989-1995 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    Lists of ad hoc committees and members, with cover letters to Mazur from AFL-CIO president Lane Kirkland
  - AFL-CIO-Committee on Political Education (COPE), 1994 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    See also Legislative & Political; see also Executive Council Reports 1994 Memo from director Richard Walsh re midterm congressional elections, with attached draft of Congressional District Coordinator Manual analyzing approval ratings, voter turnout, other strategic indicators, August 10, 1994
  - AFL-CIO-Committee on Political Education (COPE), 1988-1992 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    See also Legislative & Political 1992 Delegate Selection manual (for selecting delegates to the national party presidential nominating conventions); memo to Mazur from David Wells re presidential nominating convention delegate selection, with attached materials, October 29, 1991; memo re Civil Rights Act of 1991, April 12, 1991; COPE Report on Senate and Gubernatorial races around the country, February 1990; letter to Mazur from COPE requesting the services of David Wells in participating on COPE Committee on Reapportionment and Redistricting, with affirmative letter in reply, July 7-19, 1989; list of talking points to present to COPE (NY State Federation?) Advisory Council re trade legislation, approach to elected officials previously supported by labor, August 28, 1988; receipts for two $3,000 contributions from ILGWU Campaign Committee, March and April 1989
  - AFL-CIO-Committee on Political Education (COPE), 1985-1987 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    Correspondence re New York State AFL-CIO Committee on Political Education (COPE) conference, July 17-21, 1985; list of NY state legislators, voting scores, and challengers, February 12, 1986; COPE Report, February 1986; remarks presented to the AFL-CIO COPE Operating Committee on behalf of Sen. Quentin N. Burdick (D.-N. Dakota), February 16, 1987; memo to Mazur with questions for presidential candidates re foreign trade, budget deficit, human needs, the political process; timetable for endorsement; text of video question for presidential candidates, 1987
  - AFL-CIO-Community Services Program, 1990 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    Draft statement by AFL-CIO Executive Council on AFL-CIO Community Services Policy, including strike assistance, retaining, retiree programs, May 1990